你好，我是菲比布非 我底下有寶寶要出來
I'm Phoebe Buffay,and I have babies coming out.
Have you started having contractions?
好，你開始陣痛了嗎？
Not yet. I heard they really hurt. Do they?
還沒，聽說會很痛，真的嗎？
Oh,my God!
這麼嘛… 天哪
Which of you is the father?
哪一位是父親？
None of them are. The father is my brother.
他們都不是，我弟才是
好
I'll miss watching you freak people out like that.
我一定會很懷念你那樣嚇別人
This is for the babies to look at someday.
菲比，快，這是要給寶寶看的
Do you want to say anything before it starts?
在生產前你有話要說嗎？ 好
Hi,kids! It's me,Aunt Phoebe.
孩子們，我是菲比姑姑
Can't wait to see you. Please don't hurt me!
真想趕快見到你們 請不要弄痛我
What took you so long?
你們怎麼那麼慢？
Your cab left when ours did.
兩輛車是一起出發的
We went back because I forgot my jacket.
我們回去拿我的外套
沒錯
You're not wearing one.
你沒穿外套啊
Oh,man! I did it again!
真是的，我又忘了
Someone has to call Frank and Alice.
得有人通知法蘭克和愛麗絲
My mom might What are you doing?
我媽也想…喬伊，你幹什麼？
I've got to get the "before" shot!
我得拍生產前的鏡頭
The One With The Triplets AKA The One Hundredth
本集播出：「生產記」
rainystar壓制ipod-mp4
We spoke to the nurse. The reason your doctor is late...
我們問過護士了 你的醫生之所以遲到是因為
...is because she's not coming.
她不來了
She hit her head in the shower.
什麼？ 她在浴室跌倒撞到頭
Oh,my God. She's so stupid!
天哪，那個蠢女人
Phoebe,it's gonna be okay.
菲比，不會有事的
I don't see three kids coming out of your vagina!
你說得輕鬆 你的陰道又沒有寶寶要出來
Listen. The nurse said the doctor is wonderful.
聽著，護士說這個醫生很好
He's head of the department.
對，他是婦產科主任
All right. Oh,dear God,save me!
老天爺救救我 怎麼了？
I'm having my first contraction!
第一次陣痛來了
Oh,it's not bad.
還好嘛 好
And so the miracle of birth begins. And l
生命的奇跡開始了…
You okay?
你沒事吧？
Something hurts.
有個地方好痛
It's sympathy pains. That's so sweet!
是感同身受，好感人喔
I didn't know I cared that much.
我不知道我有那麼在意
I'm Dr. Harad. I'll be delivering your babies.
我是哈洛醫生 我負責替你接生
You'll be in good hands. I've been doing this a long time.
有我在你放心，我是老手了
I'll be back to do your internal.
我馬上回來幫你做檢查
Just relax,everything looks great.
你先放輕鬆，目前一切都很好
And also,I love Fonzie.
還有，我愛方奇
Did he just say he loves Fonzie?
他剛才說他愛方奇嗎？
That's what it sounded like.
聽起來是
All right.
好
Am I late? Nobody came out yet,right?
我來晚了嗎？ 還沒有人出來吧？
No,we haven't started yet. Where's Alice?
沒有，還沒開始呢 愛麗絲呢？
Delaware. Until she gets here, I'll be your coach.
在德拉威，不過她正在趕來 目前先由我充當教練
Don't worry. She told me about the LaMazda stuff.
放心，她有教我拉馬茲什麼的
If you get the babies out by month's end...
就是在月底前生產
...you get two percent financing.
就能獲得2%的補助
對
Monica,you're gonna be very proud of me.
摩妮卡，你一定會很以我為榮
I just got us dates with two unbelievably cute nurses.
我幫我們約到兩個俏護士
Oh,my!
喔
They're male nurses.
是男看護
Not in my head.
在我想像中不是
They want to take us out Saturday night! What do you say?
總之他們約我們週六晚上出去 如何？
I don't think so.
我看算了
What are you talking about?
什麼？什麼叫算了？
You've been telling me to get over Ross and move on.
是你勸我忘記羅斯向前看的
I'm moving on and so are you.
我向前看了，你得陪我
Why don't you want to go?
你說，你為什麼不去
Why don't you give me a good reason...
不如你說一個理由
...and I'll tell you if it's true.
我再告訴你是對是錯
-What? -Harder than it sounds,isn't it?
什麼？ 沒那麼簡單吧
You're coming. And when they get off...
總之你也要去
...we'll go get some Jello with them.
我還答應他們下班一起吃果凍
There's always room for Jello.
沒錯，人永遠吃得下果凍
How do you make that dirty?
你為什麼能說得那麼色？
It's easy. I can do it with anything.
簡單，我什麼都能說得很色 你聽
Grandma's chicken salad....
奶奶的雞肉沙拉…
Get a shot of this.
羅斯，拍這裡
These are the headlines when you were born.
寶寶們 這是你們出生當天的頭條
Now,girl baby,turn away. And boy babies...
女寶寶把頭轉開，男寶寶…
...check it out!
看，
This is what naked women looked like when you were born.
這就是你出生當月的裸女
Now let's dive into the good stuff.
盡情欣賞吧
Okay,I'm having another one!
好，陣痛又來了
This one doesn't hurt eith Yes,it does!
這次也不太痛…錯，很痛
I was kind of hoping that was it.
我有點希望已經生了
Where are Monica and Rachel,anyway?
摩妮卡和瑞秋呢？
A couple of nurses asked them out.
可能跟約她們的護士在一起
Really? Male nurses?
是嗎？男看護？
Yeah,I was bummed too.
對，我也很失望
So they're going on dates.
她們要去約會？
-When? -I think Saturday.
什麼時候？星期六吧…
-What's with him? -Sympathy pains.
他怎麼了？ 他感同身受
It was sweet at first,but now I think he's trying to steal my thunder.
我本來很感動 現在我覺得他只是想搶鋒頭
Let's see what we got here.
好，來看看你的情況
Oh,you know,Fonzie dated triplets.
你知道嗎？ 方奇跟三胞胎約過會
This Fonzie person you keep referring to...
你一直提到的這位方奇 ？
...is that another doctor?
他是另一位醫生嗎
Oh,no,no.
不是
Fonzie is the nickname of Arthur Fonzerelli.
方奇是亞瑟方塞瑞利的匿稱
The Fonz.
也叫方子
All right.
好
It's not that weird,is it?
其實不會很怪吧？
It's very weird!
怪得不得了
I don't want some guy down there telling me I'm "dilated-a-mundo."
我才不要聽某人告訴我 我擴張了「一滴滴」
He doesn't seem to be impersonating Fonzie
老實說，他不是在模仿方奇…
What are you doing?
你在幹什麼？
Why are you defending him? Just get me another doctor...
幹嘛替他辯解？去幫我另外找一個
...who isn't crazy and doesn't Fonzie!
沒有發瘋 不是方奇的醫生
Again,it's not
其實他不是…
Hey,there you are!
你在這裡
There's something you should know.
有件事應該讓你知道
Is this about you dating the nurse? Joey told me.
是你要跟護士約會的事嗎？我聽喬伊說了
I am so fine. You and l, we're just nothing.
我一點也不在意 你和我又沒什麼
Just goofing around.
我們只是玩玩
I was about to tell you I was getting out of it.
其實我是想告訴你我打算推掉
But if we're just "goofing around," maybe I will go out with him.
既然我們只是玩玩 那我就跟他出去好了
Fine. Maybe I will too.
好，那我也要
Hey! Look what I found in the gift shop.
喂，你們看我去禮品部…
Get up! Get up! Get up!
起來，快起來
This is Dr. Oberman.
菲比，這是歐伯曼醫生
He has no strong feelings about Fonzie...
他對「幸福時光」的所有人物
...or any of the Happy Days gang.
都沒什麼感覺
You're going into what grade?
你要升幾年級？
I'm actually a first-year resident. I graduated early.
我剛升住院醫師 常有人那樣問我，我提前…
Me too.
我也是
I should have specified I'd need a grown-up doctor.
羅斯，或許我應該強調 我是要已成年的醫師
Really,I'm fully qualified
我絕對有能力…
Doogie!
Doesn't anybody understand that I'm going to be having babies soon?
到底有沒有人瞭解我快生了？
Go,little boy! Go!
你走，走啊 小毛頭
Oh,cool. You made him cry!
你把他弄哭了
Mr. Tribbiani,I'm afraid you've got kidney stones.
崔比亞尼先生，你有腎結石
Well,what else could it be?
有別的可能嗎？
It's kidney stones.
就是腎結石
Or....
或是…？
Kidney stones.
腎結石
-lf it was something else? -Well,that would be "kidney stones."
如果是別的毛病… 絕對是腎結石
You're getting there.
差不多了
These babies are very,very lucky.
這些寶寶很幸運
They are? Why?
是嗎，為什麼？
They'll be born on the Fonz's half-birthday.
他們的生日日期是方子的一半
Happy Birthday.
生日快樂
Just to clarify...
我澄清一下，
...I'm not Fonzie.
我不是方奇
It's a terrific thing that you're having these babies for Frank and Alice.
說真的 你能替你弟生孩子真的很棒
No,it is.
的確
Can I tell you a secret?
我可以告訴你一個秘密嗎？ 你說
I want to keep one.
我要自己留一個
Oh,I'm gonna be on the news.
天哪，我會上新聞
You must be kidding.
菲比，別開玩笑了
You know you can't keep one of these babies.
你明知你不能這麼做
Maybe I can. You don't know.
為什麼？搞不好可以 你怎麼知道
I do. Frank and Alice will want to keep all their children.
我當然知道 法蘭克他們一定三個都要
Maybe not. You know?
不一定
Three babies are a handful.
三個寶寶很多
Maybe they'll want to unload one.
也許他們正在找機會送走一個
I hate to miss an opportunity because I didn't ask.
我不想因為沒開口而失去機會
Phoebe,no. This is insane.
菲比，這件事太扯了
Just ask him.
你就問問看嘛
What? Me?
我？
I can't ask him!
我不能自己問
Do you know how inappropriate that would be?
你知道那樣多不成體統嗎？
All I'm saying is, just talk to Frank.
總之你去找法蘭克談
Just feel him out.
探探他的口風
No. I will not ask Frank to give you one of his kids.
不行，我怎麼能叫法蘭克 送你一個孩子
You're right.
你說得對
Tell him it's for you.
就說是你要的
Feeling better,sweetie?
好一點了嗎？
Maybe a little.
一點點吧
Wish you hadn't seen me throw up.
真希望你沒看到我吐
Me too.
我也希望
I just heard. What's up?
我剛剛聽說，怎麼回事？
Kidney stones!
腎結石
Ordinarily,we try to break the stones up with shock waves.
通常我們會用衝擊波震碎結石
But they're too close to the bladder.
但你的結石已經太靠近膀胱
Either we wait for you to pass them or else go up the urethra
不是等你排尿排出來 就是從尿道往上…
No,no,no,no. Nothing is going up,okay?
不行，不能往上 絕對不考慮往上
Up is not an option. What's a urethra?
尿道是什麼？
Are you crazy?
你瘋了嗎？
Did you ask him?
你問他了嗎？
No,I haven't had a chance yet.
我還沒有機會跟他獨處
I'm kind of on a clock here.
我的時間有限
Oh,Fonzie.
方奇
You know who I always liked? Mork.
我一直都很喜歡魔克
Undo it. Undo it.
收回收回收回
Fonzie met Mork.
方奇遇見魔克
Mork froze Fonzie.
魔克把方奇結凍
對
But Fonzie was already cool.
但是方奇本來就很酷「冷」
So he wasn't hurt. Right?
所以他不會有事，對吧？
Yeah,that's right.
也對
How you doing?
你好嗎？
Okay. Doctor says any minute now.
很好，醫生說隨時都會生
You know,Alice is going to be here so soon.
愛麗絲馬上就會到
You couldn't just do me a favor and,like,hold them in?
你能不能幫個忙… 先憋住？
Sorry,I'm in the middle of the last favor you asked me to do.
抱歉，我正在處理 你請我幫的最後一個忙
This is Dan,one of the guys we're dating on Saturday.
他是丹 我們星期六的男伴之一
Nice to meet you.
很高興認識你
「他是你的」
I'm really looking forward to Saturday night. Really!
你好，我很期待星期六的約會 非常期待
So,Dan...
丹，
...nurse,not a doctor,huh?
你是護士不是醫生？
Kind of girlie,isn't it?
有點娘娘腔對吧？
That's okay. I'm doing this to get through medical school.
沒關係 這只是醫學院的實習學分
And it didn't feel "girlie" during the Gulf War.
而且波灣戰爭時 感覺沒那麼娘娘腔
Sure.
那當然
Thanks for doing that for us, by the way.
感謝你保家衛國
Why wait till Saturday? Are you free tomorrow?
何必等到星期六 你明天有空嗎？
Sure. I'll get somebody to cover me.
行啊，我找人代班
Great!
太好了
Hey,you and me,Saturday night?
我們星期六去約個會如何？
-No. -All right,very good!
不要 很好
This is a big one.
這一回很痛
Get these things out of me!
把它弄出來
Breathe! Breathe through the pain.
深呼吸，深呼吸可以止痛
I want the drugs,Ross!
我想吃止痛藥！我想吃止痛藥
I do too! I do too!
我也是！我也是
Yeah,I love you. Okay,bye.
我愛你，再見
That was Alice's mom. Alice left five hours ago.
愛麗絲的媽說她出發5小時了
She should be here.
她早就該到了
She'll make it on time.
放心，她會趕上的 好
So,Frank...
法蘭克，
...three babies. That just seems like a lot,huh?
三個寶寶耶 還真多，對吧？
Not to me.
我不覺得
Fair enough.
很好
You're at ten centimeters. Time to start having babies.
擴張10公分，該生了
I want only the father here.
請父親留下來就好
-We love you. -Good luck.
菲比再見 加油
愛你哦
丹，再見 再見，摩妮卡
再見
I need a clamp,a sterile towel and Channel 31.
我要產鉗，消毒毛巾 和31頻道
What is that?
那是什麼？
Oh,my God!
天哪
Oh,no,no! It's a good one. Fonzie plays the bongos.
不會，這一集很棒 方奇會打手鼓
Ready? Time to try pushing.
準備好了嗎？該用力了
Ready? Time to try peeing.
準備好了嗎？該撒尿了
Wait,wait,wait,wait! It's almost time to try peeing.
等等！是差不多該撒尿了
Push. Concentrate on pushing.
用力，很好，專心用力
I see the head.
有了，我看到頭了
Yes,it has a head!
萬歲！他有頭
Keep pushing. Come on.
繼續用力，加油
I can't believe somebody's coming out!
居然有人從你肚子裡跑出來
There's somebody coming out of you!
有人從你肚子裡跑出來
-It's my son! -All right.
是我兒子
Here's your first baby!
這是你的第一個寶寶
Yes! We got a baby boy!
萬歲！小男生出來了
Frank Junior,Junior!
法蘭克二世二世
How does he look?
他長得怎樣？
So gross!
噁心死了
Okay. You ready to push again?
可以再用力了嗎？
I already had a baby. Leave me alone!
我已經生一個了，不要煩我
Come on,you can do it! You can do it!
加油，你一定行
Little Leslie's here! We got another one!
萬歲！小萊絲莉出來了
Oh,my God! I can't believe I have two children.
天哪，我居然有兩個孩子了
How scary is that?
真嚇人
Come on,little Chandler, it's time to be born.
小錢德，該出來了 快啊，小錢德
He's coming! Yes,he's coming!
他出來了，他出來了
Hey,where's his thing?
他的小象呢？
Chandler's a girl!
錢德是女生
Oh,God! Kindergarten flashback.
天哪，幼稚園回憶重現
They read the sonogram wrong, because they thought it was a boy.
一定是照超音波看錯了 醫生以為是個男生
But Chandler's a girl!
但錢德是女生！錢德是女生
Okay,keep saying it.
很好，繼續叫
Am I too late?
我來晚了嗎？
No,no. Everything's okay.
不會，一切都很好
There's 30 fingers and 30 toes.
每個寶寶都好手好腳的
We have our babies?
我們的孩子生了？ 對
We have our babies.
我們有孩子了
Oh,my God!
天哪
You did it,man.
你辦到了
Would you like to see them?
你要看看它們嗎？
They're so small.
好小喔
-I'll call you tomorrow. -Great.
我明天跟你聯絡 好
Are you really going to date that nurse man?
你真的要跟那個護士男約會？
You and I are just "goofing around."
你和我只是玩玩
I thought,why not "goof around" with him?
我當然也可以跟他玩玩
I don't know if you've looked up "goofing around" in the dictionary.
我不知道你有沒有查過字典
Well,I have...
我有，
...and the technical definition is:
「玩玩」的定義是
Two friends who care a lot about each other...
兩個好朋友，非常在乎對方
...and have amazing sex...
在床上很「性」福
...and just want to spend more time together.
而且想多跟對方相處
But if you have this new dictionary that gets you mad at me...
如果你用的是讓你生氣的版本
...then we have to get you my original one.
那我們應該買我的版本給你
I am so bad at this.
我實在很不會拗
-You're better than you think you are. -Really?
比你想像的要好 真的？
Okay. So if?
好，那…
-Know when to stop. -I sensed that I should stop.
要見好就收 我也覺得夠了
So we're okay?
我們沒事了？ 沒事了
I'm gonna go tell Dan that it's not gonna happen.
我去告訴丹我不跟他約會了
-Don't do the dance. -Right.
不要跳舞 好
You're my favorite.
我覺得我最喜歡你
-Which one do you have? -I don't care.
你抱的是哪一個？ 無所謂
Frank and Alice want me to tell you they're making phone calls.
法蘭克和愛麗絲說 他們還要打電話
Did you talk to them about,you know....
你有沒有問他們… 這個嘛…
No,honey.
沒有
好
It was a long shot.
反正也不太可能
You guys? Can I just have a second alone with the babies?
讓我跟寶寶獨處一下好嗎？ 好
So here you are.
你們都在了
Seems like yesterday I was talking to you in that petri dish.
我對著培養皿跟你們說話 彷彿是昨天的事
Everyone said labor was the hardest thing.
大家都說生產最難熬
But they were wrong. This is.
其實跟你們分開才是
Well,I had the most fun with you guys.
這段日子真的很開心
I wish I could take you home and see you every day.
真想帶你們回家每天看著你們
I'll settle for being your favorite aunt.
我就當你們最喜歡的姑姑吧
I know Alice's sister has a pool, but you lived in me.
愛麗絲的妹妹家有游泳池 但你們在我肚子裡游過
Okay,so we're cool.
那就這樣了
We're gonna be great.
我們會處得很好
Little high-fives.
擊掌
Well,if you're going to cry....
既然你都哭了
Phoebe,we are so proud of you. You're amazing!
菲比，我們好以你為榮 你真了不起
I know.
我知道
Does it hurt as bad as they say?
真的有那麼痛嗎？
You won't be able to take it.
有，你絕對受不了
Now that little Chandler is a girl, what'll they name her?
既然小錢德是個女生 他們打算叫她什麼？
They'll call her Chandler.
就叫她錢德
Kind of a masculine name, don't you think?
這個名字有點男性化吧？
It works on you.
你都能用了
Maybe they can girlie it up a bit, like Chandlerette.
也許可以把它女性化 例如錢蒂葉特
Alice called her Channy-fanny.
愛麗絲叫她錢妮潘妮
Ha-ha,Channy-fanny.
錢妮潘妮